<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on </title>
    <link>/tags/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>info@sambw.me (Sam Bennett-Williams)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>info@sambw.me (Sam Bennett-Williams)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Sam Bennett-Williams</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hume’s Problem of Induction</title>
      <link>/posts/9--humes-problem-of-induction-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>info@sambw.me (Sam Bennett-Williams)</author>
      <guid>/posts/9--humes-problem-of-induction-essay/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was recently going through documents on my computer and came across a paper I wrote for my Epistemology philosophy class in college. As I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a solid idea for a blog topic this week, and do really find the content interesting, I thought I would share. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;humes-problem-of-induction--an-essay&#34;&gt;Hume&amp;rsquo;s Problem of Induction- an essay&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The 17th century Polish alchemist Michael Sendivogius once said &amp;ldquo;Experience is the sole teacher of truth.&amp;rdquo; This is the essence of the scientific and Empiricist mind and in my view completely true. But what can experience tell us? In Hume’s &lt;em&gt;An Enquiry concerning Human understanding&lt;/em&gt; he relates his problem of induction and its consequences for Epistemology. This essay will show that rationalism is not the answer, lay out Hume’s argument and conclusions, and show that our grasp of knowledge is impossible for the time being.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harper</title>
      <link>/posts/8--harper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>info@sambw.me (Sam Bennett-Williams)</author>
      <guid>/posts/8--harper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another starter for you, I would actually love comments on, feel free to send me some feedback! &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:writing@sambw.me&#34;&gt;writing@sambw.me&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;harper&#34;&gt;Harper&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Detective Strauss stepped through the hospital&amp;rsquo;s double front door and immediately wanted a smoke. There was just something about hospitals that got under his skin. He gritted his teeth and pushed the feeling down. He was a cop damnit and on duty. Getting his bearings, he made his way to the ER wing, where he found a very green and stiff uniform standing outside a curtained off area.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
